

Website: kolev.io

Email: p.kolev22@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/plamen-k

Linkedln: https://www.linkedin.com/in/plamen-kolev-465915a7

ABOUT

My name is Plamen Kolev and I am a Manchester based developer specializing in web application development, system automation and web application deployment. I enjoy playing with emerging technologies and love to build and test software.

I have worked with Perl, Bash, Python, PHP, Ruby and Enterprise Java. I am a strong advocate of Linux and love working with open-source technologies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, The Hut Group

August 2017 - Present

Worked on the in-house warehouse management system as part of the Internal Movements Team. Delivered features in **Agile** environment. Also wrote a library for testing and automation to accelerate the development process, please ask me about it!

Software Engineer Intern, Intel Corporation

August 2015 - September 2016

Worked on high-performing, Cyber Security projects. Created automated tests using BASH, Perl and in-house tools. Developed scripts to automate product integration and deployment as part of a large, multi-national team.

Interviewer, Populus Data Solutions

April 2014 - June 2015

Conducted national studies across Britain on sociopolitical issues

EDUCATION

BSc. Computer Science, Newcastle University

September 2013 - June 2017

Achieved First Class Honours degree in Computer Science with Industrial Placement. Studied software design & development. RDB technologies, Computer Architecture: Parallel computing and biocomputing.

PROJECTS

Web Platform for Digital Deployment of Virtual Servers

November 2016 - June 2017

Created a platform for deployment, management and monitoring of virtual servers as part of BSC final year dissertation. Technologies used: Puppet, BASH shell, Virtualbox, Vagrant, Ruby, Ruby On Rails.

Neven Body care

5 August - 28 August 2016

Created a PHP website for the Neven brand as part of a case study for creating web platforms. The project aimed to create an interactive system for featuring natural care products.

Secure Coding Presentation

5 May 2016

Gave a presentation in Leicester College about different ways code can be exploited by a malicious user and ways to mitigate and avoid such cases.

Lloyds Banking

31 October 2014

Developed and designed a website with restful API that hooks to an Android application for the British bank Lloyds. The product was produced as part of a team project.

HackNE Hackathon

31 October 2014

Co-organized a hackathon in the North East, United Kingdom backed by Major League Hacking EU. Created the website for the event, PR and print design materials.

PAConsulting

12 February 2014

Developed an environmental friendly hardware & software solution with the Raspberry Pi that involves predictive light automation and control.